# SRUJAL PATEL

London, UK - <u>srujal.patel02@gmail.com</u> - (+44) 7469 686171 <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/iamsrujal/</u>

### **Personal Profile**

First-hand experience in analysis, development, and implementation in **JavaScript, Object-Oriented concepts**. Enthusiastic collaborator, an adaptive person with creative **problem solving**, and **good communication skills**. keen interest in technology, mobile applications, web applications, and user experiences. continually evaluating and upgrading my skills so that I stay at the forefront of web development.a natural analytical person, who has proven himself by completing projects for IT consultancies, software houses, web design agencies, and IT departments.

### **Work Experience**

### **Junior Front End Web Developer**

My Utility Genius - Apr 2021 to Present

- Utilise established development tools, guidelines, and conventions, including but not limited to Visual Studio, ASP.NET, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and C#/VB.NET, Angular.
- Create and deliver data-driven reports.
- Design, code, and test new Windows and Web software applications.
- Enhance existing systems by analysing business objectives, preparing an action plan, and identifying areas for modification and improvement.
- Maintain existing software systems by identifying and correcting software defects.
- Investigate and develop skills in new technologies.
- Create technical specifications and test plans.
- Create new and extend existing operational documentation.
- Consult colleagues concerning the maintenance and performance of software systems.

### **Full-Stack Web Developer**

Freelancer (Self Employed) - May 2020 to Jan 2021

Participated in the **frontend and backend web application** life cycle. gathered requirements from the client, understood and integrated them into the Web architecture.

- Fixed bugs in existing projects.
- Contributed inputs into video chatting app by creating screen sharing, one to one as well as group messaging functionality using WebRTC and socket IO.

### Web Developer

### Magneto IT Solutions Pvt. Ltd – Jan 2019 to May 2020

It was my responsibility to integrate Web pages using standard **HTML and CSS** best practices. managed JavaScript frameworks by converting HTML pages.

- Involved in a stock market application in which CRON was used to cluster in NodeJS, which helped reduce the time complexity to 70%.
- Developed a social media app which used to connect people based on their relationship(department) like HR, developer, sales. Tech Used: amCharts, D3 Chart, Neo4j, Angular, and NodeJS.
- Implemented and optimised complex SQL queries.
- Also contributed to the team by training and sharing my knowledge with the new candidates in JavaScript frameworks and database architectures.

### Skills

Frameworks	Angular, React, Vue.js, Node.js, Bootstrap
Languages	Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS
Integration/Versioning Tools	Git, GitHub, GitLab, Bitbucket
Architecture Models	MVC, SOA
Databases	MySQL, Neo4j, MongoDB

Cloud hosting	GCP, AWS
Designer tools	Microsoft Visio, Adobe Photoshop
Scripting	jQuery, JavaScript, TypeScript
Platforms	Windows, Ubuntu. Unix
IDEs955	VS Code, Atom, NetBeans, Eclipse

#### Education

**MSc Advanced Computer Science**University Of Hertfordshire

From 01/2021 to 01/2023

Grade: 4.25

Master of Computer Application Charusat University From 09/2016 to 05/2019

Bachelor in Advanced Accounting Anand Commerce College

From 06/2010 to 04/2013

### **Certifications and Licenses**

- Java tutorial course SoloLearn Oct 2017 to Present
- Introduction to modern application development NPTEL Mar 2018 to Present
- PHP tutorial course SoloLearn Aug 2019 to Present
- Neo4j certified professional Database Oct 2019 to Present
- JavaScript tutorial course SoloLearn Oct 2019 to Present

## **Projects**

### **Bazarlinks**

BAZARLINKS.COM provides links to the business associations or professionals associated with every type of manufacturer, wholesaler, retailer, homemade product industry, and commerce service. In the beginning, I built this project in **ASP.Net** and later converted the whole website into **core PHP**.

Demo: Business Links Provider

### **NPM Package**

Array-refactor is refactoring any sensitive data in user collection or any personal data. Currently, by using array-refactor, you can remove that sensitive data before transferring it to logs or the public. There are many uses of array-refactor. This npm package is not dependent on any third-party library, instead, it is built on **JavaScript** predefined functions like map and filter.

Demo: <u>array-refactor - npm</u>

# JustURL - Web Application

The main use of our Web application is sharing URLs (links) with friends, colleagues, and our beloved connections. This application is built on **angular 10** and I have integrated **server-side rendering** for SEO optimization and deploy into the **google cloud platform**. All APIs are built on cloud infrastructure with cloud functions.

Demo: JustURL - Tool To Shorten A Long URL

Reference is available upon request.